<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dnd SYSTEM "../dtd/dnd.dtd">
<?xml-model href="../xsd/dnd.xsd"?>
<dnd>
    <!-- personajes -->
    <characters>
        <!-- nivel -->
        <character level="1" id="b1">
            <!-- clases -->
            <class>
                <name>Barbarian</name>
                <levels>1</levels>
            </class>
            <!-- datos basicos -->
            <race>Human</race>
            <ac>13</ac>
            <hitpoints>15</hitpoints>
            <!-- competencias -->
            <proficiencies>
                <armor>ligth, medium, shield</armor>
                <weapon>martial, simple</weapon>
                <tool>no</tool>
                <saving_throw>str, con</saving_throw>
                <skill>athletic, deception, insight, survival</skill>
            </proficiencies>
            <!-- puntuaciones de caracteristicas -->
            <stats>
                <str>16</str>
                <dex>11</dex>
                <con>16</con>
                <int>10</int>
                <wis>14</wis>
                <cha>10</cha>
            </stats>
            <features>
                <!-- dotes -->
                <feature>Rage: In battle, you fight with primal ferocity. On your turn, you can
                    enter a rage as a bonus action. While raging, you gain the following benefits if
                    you aren’t wearing heavy armor: -You have advantage on Strength checks and
                    Strength saving throws. -When you make a melee weapon attack using Strength, you
                    gain a bonus to the damage roll that increases as you gain levels as a
                    barbarian, as shown in the Rage Damage column of the Barbarian table. -You have
                    resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage. If you are able to
                    cast spells, you can’t cast them or concentrate on them while raging. Your rage
                    lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are knocked unconscious or if your turn
                    ends and you haven’t attacked a hostile creature since your last turn or taken
                    damage since then. You can also end your rage on your turn as a bonus action.
                    Once you have raged the number of times shown for your barbarian level in the
                    Rages column of the Barbarian table, you must finish a long rest before you can
                    rage again.</feature>
                <feature>Unarmored defense: While you are not wearing any armor, your Armor⁠ Class
                    equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Constitution modifier. You can use a
                    shield and still gain this benefit.</feature>
            </features>
            <inventory>
                <!-- objetos -->
                <item>Battleaxe</item>
                <item>Handaxe</item>
                <item>Explorer's Pack</item>
                <item>Javelin</item>
                <item>Backpack</item>
                <item>Bedroll</item>
                <item>Mess Kit</item>
                <item>Tinderbox</item>
                <item>Torch</item>
                <item>Ration</item>
                <item>Waterskin</item>
                <item>Hempen Rope</item>
            </inventory>
            <!-- imagen -->
            <img>barbarian</img>
            <link>https://https://www.dndbeyond.com/classes/barbarian</link>
        </character>
        <!-- nivel -->
        <character level="4" id="b2">
            <!-- clases -->
            <class>
                <name>Warlock</name>
                <levels>2</levels>
            </class>
            <class>
                <name>Sorcerer</name>
                <levels>2</levels>
            </class>
            <!-- datos basicos -->
            <race>Tiefling</race>
            <ac>13</ac>
            <hitpoints>19</hitpoints>
            <!-- competencias -->
            <proficiencies>
                <armor>ligth</armor>
                <weapon>simple</weapon>
                <tool>no</tool>
                <saving_throw>wis, cha</saving_throw>
                <skill>deception, insight, intimidation, religion</skill>
            </proficiencies>
            <!-- espacios de conjuro -->
            <spell_slot>
                <lv1>5</lv1>
                <lv2>0</lv2>
                <lv3>0</lv3>
                <lv4>0</lv4>
                <lv5>0</lv5>
                <lv6>0</lv6>
                <lv7>0</lv7>
                <lv8>0</lv8>
                <lv9>0</lv9>
            </spell_slot>
            <!-- puntuaciones de caracteristicas -->
            <stats>
                <str>8</str>
                <dex>15</dex>
                <con>8</con>
                <int>9</int>
                <wis>15</wis>
                <cha>17</cha>
            </stats>
            <!-- dotes -->
            <features>
                <feature>Dark One's Blessing: Starting at 1st level, when you reduce a hostile
                    creature to 0 hit points, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Charisma
                    modifier + your warlock level (minimum of 1).</feature>
                <feature>Hellish Resistance: You have resistance to fire damage.</feature>
                <feature>Darkvision: Thanks to your infernal heritage, you have superior vision in
                    dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it
                    were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern
                    color in darkness, only shades of gray.</feature>
                <feature>Eldritch Invocations: In your study of occult lore, you have unearthed
                    eldritch invocations, fragments of forbidden knowledge that imbue you with an
                    abiding magical ability. At 2nd level, you gain two eldritch invocations of your
                    choice. Your invocation options are detailed at the end of the class
                    description. When you gain certain warlock levels, you gain additional
                    invocations of your choice, as shown in the Invocations Known column of the
                    Warlock table. Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose
                    one of the invocations you know and replace it with another invocation that you
                    could learn at that level.</feature>
                <feature>Eldritch Invocation: Agonizing Blast: When you cast eldritch blast, add
                    your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.</feature>
                <feature>Eldritch Invocation: Repelling Blast: When you hit a creature with eldritch
                    blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</feature>
                <feature>Sorcery Points: At 2nd level, you tap into a deep wellspring of magic
                    within yourself. This wellspring is represented by sorcery points, which allow
                    you to create a variety of magical effects. You have 2 sorcery points, and you
                    gain more as you reach higher levels, as shown in the Sorcery Points column of
                    the Sorcerer table. You can never have more sorcery points than shown on the
                    table for your level. You regain all spent sorcery points when you finish a long
                    rest.</feature>
                <feature>Flexible Casting: You can use your sorcery points to gain additional spell
                    slots, or sacrifice spell slots to gain additional sorcery points. You learn
                    other ways to use your sorcery points as you reach higher levels. Creating Spell
                    Slots. You can transform unexpended sorcery points into one spell slot as a
                    bonus action on your turn. The Creating Spell Slots table shows the cost of
                    creating a spell slot of a given level. You can create spell slots no higher in
                    level than 5th. A 1st level Spell Slot cost 2 Sorcery Points A 2nd level Spell
                    Slot cost 3 Sorcery Points A 3rd level Spell Slot cost 5 Sorcery Points A 4th
                    level Spell Slot cost 6 Sorcery Points A 5th level Spell Slot cost 7 Sorcery
                    Points Converting a Spell Slot to Sorcery Points. As a bonus action on your
                    turn, you can expend one spell slot and gain a number of sorcery points equal to
                    the slot’s level.</feature>
                <feature>Flexible Casting: You can use your sorcery points to gain additional spell
                    slots, or sacrifice spell slots to gain additional sorcery points. You learn
                    other ways to use your sorcery points as you reach higher levels. Creating Spell
                    Slots. You can transform unexpended sorcery points into one spell slot as a
                    bonus action on your turn. The Creating Spell Slots table shows the cost of
                    creating a spell slot of a given level. You can create spell slots no higher in
                    level than 5th. A 1st level Spell Slot cost 2 Sorcery Points A 2nd level Spell
                    Slot cost 3 Sorcery Points A 3rd level Spell Slot cost 5 Sorcery Points A 4th
                    level Spell Slot cost 6 Sorcery Points A 5th level Spell Slot cost 7 Sorcery
                    Points Converting a Spell Slot to Sorcery Points. As a bonus action on your
                    turn, you can expend one spell slot and gain a number of sorcery points equal to
                    the slot’s level.</feature>
                <feature>Draconic Interactions: Whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting
                    with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</feature>
                <feature>Draconic Resiliance: As magic flows through your body, it causes physical
                    traits of your dragon ancestors to emerge. At 1st level, your hit point maximum
                    increases by 1 and increases by 1 again whenever you gain a level in this class.
                    Additionally, parts of your skin are covered by a thin sheen of dragon-like
                    scales. When you aren’t wearing armor, your AC equals 13 + your Dexterity
                    modifier.</feature>
                <feature>Dragon Ancestor - Copper: Your dragon ancestor type is copper. The
                    associated damage type is acid.</feature>
                <feature>Infernal Legacy: You know the thaumaturgy cantrip. When you reach 3rd
                    level, you can cast the hellish rebuke spell as a 2nd-level spell once with this
                    trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Charisma is
                    your spellcasting ability for these spells.</feature>
            </features>
            <!-- objetos -->
            <inventory>
                <item>Prayer Boock</item>
                <item>Arcane Focus</item>
                <item>Holy Symbol</item>
                <item>Stick of Incense</item>
                <item>Vestments</item>
                <item>Belt Pouch</item>
                <item>Dagger</item>
                <item>Dungeoneer's Pack</item>
                <item>Leather Armor</item>
                <item>Common clothes</item>
                <item>Backpack</item>
                <item>Crowbar</item>
                <item>Hammer</item>
                <item>Piton</item>
                <item>Torch</item>
                <item>Tinderbox</item>
                <item>Rations</item>
                <item>Waterskin</item>
                <item>Hempen Rope</item>
            </inventory>
            <!-- imagen -->
            <img>warlock</img>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://https://www.dndbeyond.com/classes/warlock</link>
        </character>
        <!-- nivel -->
        <character level="12" id="b3">
            <!-- clases -->
            <class>
                <name>Figther</name>
                <levels>12</levels>
            </class>
            <!-- datos basicos -->
            <race>Githyanki</race>
            <ac>16</ac>
            <hitpoints>106</hitpoints>
            <!-- competencias -->
            <proficiencies>
                <armor>ligth, medium, heavy, shield</armor>
                <weapon>martial, simple</weapon>
                <tool>no</tool>
                <saving_throw>str, con</saving_throw>
                <skill>athletic, insight, intimidation, perception</skill>
            </proficiencies>
            <!-- puntuaciones de caracteristicas -->
            <stats>
                <str>20</str>
                <dex>12</dex>
                <con>16</con>
                <int>8</int>
                <wis>14</wis>
                <cha>8</cha>
            </stats>
            <!-- dotes -->
            <features>
                <feature>Second Wind: You have a limited well of stamina that you can draw on to
                    protect yourself from harm. On your turn, you can use a bonus action to regain
                    hit points equal to 1d10 + your fighter level. Once you use this feature, you
                    must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</feature>
                <feature>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting: When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage
                    die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two
                    hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is
                    a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to
                    gain this benefit.</feature>
                <feature>Military Rank: You have a military rank from your career as a soldier.
                    Those loyal to your former military organization still recognize your authority
                    and influence, and will address you with respect if they are of a lower rank.
                    You can invoke your rank to influence other soldiers and commandeer simple
                    equipment or horses for temporary use. You can also generally have access to
                    friendly camps and forts where your military rank is recognized</feature>
                <feature>Action Surge: Starting at 2nd level, you can push yourself beyond your
                    normal limits for a moment. On your turn, you can take one additional action on
                    top of your regular action and a possible bonus action. Once you use this
                    feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</feature>
                <feature>Extra Attack: Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of
                    once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</feature>
                <feature>Indomitable: Beginning at 9th level, you can reroll a saving throw that you
                    fail. If you do so, you must use the new roll, and you can’t use this feature
                    again until you finish a long rest.</feature>
                <feature>Extra Attack: Beginning at 11th level, you can attack three times, instead
                    of twice, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</feature>
                <feature>Alert: You gain a +5 bonus to initiative and can't be Surprised.</feature>
                <feature>Great Weapon Master: When an attack with a melee weapon lands a Critical
                    Hit or kills a creature, you can make another melee weapon attack as a Bonus
                    action that turn. When attacking with a Two-Handed or Versatile melee weapon (in
                    both hands) that you are Proficient with, Attack rolls take a -5 penalty, but
                    their damage increases by 10.</feature>
                <feature>Combat Superiority: Gain 4 Superiority Dice (Subclass Feature) Choose 3
                    Manoeuvres (Subclass Feature). At level 7 you gain 1 aditional superiority dice
                    and 2 manoeuvres. At level 12 you gain 2 aditionals manoeuvres</feature>
                <feature>Improved Combat Superiority: The size of your Superiority Dice increases to
                    1d10</feature>
                <feature>Githyanki psionic: at level 1, you can cast a invisible mage hand once per
                    long rest</feature>
                <feature>Githyanki psionic(lv3): at level 3, you can cast jump once per day</feature>
                <feature>Githyanki psionic(lv5): at level 5, you can cast misty step once per day</feature>
            </features>
            <!-- objetos -->
            <inventory>
                <item>Chain Mail</item>
                <item>Greatsword</item>
                <item>Light Crossbow (Two-Handed)</item>
                <item>Crossbow bolts</item>
                <item>Dungeoneer's Pack</item>
                <item>Backpack</item>
                <item>Crowbar</item>
                <item>Hammer</item>
                <item>Piton</item>
                <item>Torch</item>
                <item>Tinderbox</item>
                <item>Rations</item>
                <item>Waterskin</item>
                <item>Hempen Rope</item>
                <item>Badge With Your Rank</item>
                <item>A Trophy Taken From A Fallen Enemy</item>
            </inventory>
            <!-- imagen -->
            <img>fighter</img>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://https://www.dndbeyond.com/classes/fighter</link>
        </character>
        <!-- nivel -->
        <character level="5" id="b4">
            <!-- clases -->
            <class>
                <name>Cleric</name>
                <levels>5</levels>
            </class>
            <!-- datos basicos -->
            <race>Half-elf</race>
            <ac>18</ac>
            <hitpoints>38</hitpoints>
            <!-- competencias -->
            <proficiencies>
                <armor>ligth, medium, heavy, shield</armor>
                <weapon>simple</weapon>
                <tool>no</tool>
                <saving_throw>wis, cha</saving_throw>
                <skill>history, insight, perception, persuasion, religion, survival</skill>
            </proficiencies>
            <!-- espacios de conjuro -->
            <spell_slot>
                <lv1>4</lv1>
                <lv2>3</lv2>
                <lv3>2</lv3>
                <lv4>0</lv4>
                <lv5>0</lv5>
                <lv6>0</lv6>
                <lv7>0</lv7>
                <lv8>0</lv8>
                <lv9>0</lv9>
            </spell_slot>
            <!-- puntuaciones de caracteristicas -->
            <stats>
                <str>12</str>
                <dex>14</dex>
                <con>16</con>
                <int>8</int>
                <wis>18</wis>
                <cha>8</cha>
            </stats>
            <!-- dotes -->
            <features>
                <feature>Ritual Casting: You can cast a cleric spell as a ritual if that spell has
                    the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.</feature>
                <feature>Disciple of Life: Also starting at 1st level, your healing spells are more
                    effective. Whenever you use a spell of 1st level or higher to restore hit points
                    to a creature, the creature regains additional hit points equal to 2 + the
                    spell's level.</feature>
                <feature>Darkvision: Thanks to your elf blood, you have superior vision in dark and
                    dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were
                    bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color
                    in darkness, only shades of gray.</feature>
                <feature>Fey Ancestry: You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed,
                    and magic can't put you to sleep.</feature>
                <feature>Shelter of the Faithful: As an acolyte, you command the respect of those
                    who share your faith, and you can perform the religious ceremonies of your
                    deity. You and your adventuring companions can expect to receive free healing
                    and care at a temple, shrine, or other established presence of your faith,
                    though you must provide any material components needed for spells. Those who
                    share your religion will support you (but only you) at a modest lifestyle. You
                    might also have ties to a specific temple dedicated to your chosen deity or
                    pantheon, and you have a residence there. This could be the temple where you
                    used to serve, or a temple where you have found a new home. While near your
                    temple, you can call upon the priests for assistance, provided the assistance
                    you ask for is not hazardous and you remain in good standing with your temple.</feature>
                <feature>Channel Divinity: At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel divine
                    energy directly from your deity, using that energy to fuel magical effects. You
                    start with two such effects: Turn Undead and an effect determined by your
                    domain. Some domains grant you additional effects as you advance in levels, as
                    noted in the domain description. When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose
                    which effect to create. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your
                    Channel Divinity again. Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws.
                    When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your cleric spell
                    save DC. Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between
                    rests, and beginning at 18th level. you can use it three times between rests.
                    When you finish a short or long rest, you regain your expended uses.</feature>
                <feature>Channel Divinity: Turn Undead: As an action, you present your holy sym⁠bol
                    and speak a prayer censuring the Undead. Each Undead that can see or hear you
                    within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its
                    saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage. A turned
                    creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and
                    it can’t willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can’t take
                    reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from
                    an effect that prevents it from moving. If there’s nowhere to move, the creature
                    can use the Dodge action.</feature>
                <feature>Channel Divinity: Preserve Life: Starting at 2nd level, you can use your
                    Channel Divinity to heal the badly injured. As an action, you present your holy
                    symbol and evoke healing energy that can restore a number of hit points equal to
                    five times your cleric level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and
                    divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no
                    more than half of its hit point maximum. You can’t use this feature on an undead
                    or a construct.</feature>
            </features>
            <!-- objetos -->
            <inventory>
                <item>Prayer Book</item>
                <item>Holy Symbol</item>
                <item>Stick of Incense</item>
                <item>Vestments</item>
                <item>Belt Pouch</item>
                <item>Mace</item>
                <item>Chain Mail</item>
                <item>Light Crossbow</item>
                <item>Crossbow bolts</item>
                <item>Priest's Pack</item>
                <item>Shield</item>
                <item>Common clothes</item>
                <item>Alms box</item>
                <item>Block of incense</item>
                <item>Censer</item>
                <item>Vestments</item>
                <item>Backpack</item>
                <item>Blanket</item>
                <item>Candle</item>
                <item>Tinderbox</item>
                <item>Rations</item>
                <item>Waterskin</item>
            </inventory>
            <!-- imagen -->
            <img>cleric</img>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://https://www.dndbeyond.com/classes/cleric</link>
        </character>
        <!-- nivel -->
        <character level="3" id="b5">
            <!-- clases -->
            <class>
                <name>Rogue</name>
                <levels>3</levels>
            </class>
            <!-- datos basicos -->
            <race> Lightfoot Halfling</race>
            <ac>14</ac>
            <hitpoints>15</hitpoints>
            <!-- competencias -->
            <proficiencies>
                <armor>ligth</armor>
                <weapon>simple, hand crossbow, longsword, rapier, shortsword</weapon>
                <tool>no</tool>
                <saving_throw>dex, int</saving_throw>
                <skill>acrobatics, deception, insight, religion, sleight of hands, stealth</skill>
            </proficiencies>
            <!-- puntuaciones de caracteristicas -->
            <stats>
                <str>8</str>
                <dex>17</dex>
                <con>8</con>
                <int>8</int>
                <wis>15</wis>
                <cha>16</cha>
            </stats>
            <!-- dotes -->
            <features>
                <feature>Thieves' Cant: During your rogue training you learned thieves’ cant, a
                    secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in
                    seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves’ cant
                    understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message⁠
                    than it does to speak the same idea plainly. In addition, you understand a set
                    of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as
                    whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves’ guild, whether loot
                    is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a
                    safe house for thieves on the run.</feature>
                <feature>Sneak Attack: Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and
                    exploit a foe’s distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 2d6 damage to
                    one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll.
                    The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon. You don’t need advantage on
                    the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that
                    enemy isn’t incapacitated, and you don’t have disadvantage on the attack roll.
                    The amount of the extra damage increases as you gain levels in this class, as
                    shown in the Sneak Attack column of the Rogue table.</feature>
                <feature>Lucky: When you roll a 1 on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw,
                    you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</feature>
                <feature>Brave: You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</feature>
                <feature>Halfling Nimbleness: You can move through the space of any creature that is
                    of a size larger than yours.</feature>
                <feature>Naturally Stealthy: You can attempt to hide even when you are obscured only
                    by a creature that is at least one size larger than you.</feature>
                <feature>Shelter of the Faithful: As an acolyte, you command the respect of those
                    who share your faith, and you can perform the religious ceremonies of your
                    deity. You and your adventuring companions can expect to receive free healing
                    and care at a temple, shrine, or other established presence of your faith,
                    though you must provide any material components needed for spells. Those who
                    share your religion will support you (but only you) at a modest lifestyle. You
                    might also have ties to a specific temple dedicated to your chosen deity or
                    pantheon, and you have a residence there. This could be the temple where you
                    used to serve, or a temple where you have found a new home. While near your
                    temple, you can call upon the priests for assistance, provided the assistance
                    you ask for is not hazardous and you remain in good standing with your temple.</feature>
                <feature>Cunning Action: Starting at 2nd level, your quick thinking and agility
                    allow you to move and act quickly. You can take a bonus action on each of your
                    turns in combat. This action can be used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or
                    Hide action.</feature>
                <feature>Fast Hands: Starting at 3rd level, you can use the bonus action granted by
                    your Cunning Action to make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check, use your
                    thieves’ tools to disarm a trap or open a lock, or take the Use an Object
                    action.</feature>
                <feature>Second-Story Work: When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain
                    the ability to climb faster than normal; climbing no longer costs you extra
                    movement. In addition, when you make a running jump, the distance you cover
                    increases by a number of feet equal to your Dexterity modifier.</feature>
            </features>
            <!-- objetos -->
            <inventory>
                <item>Prayer Wheel</item>
                <item>Holy Symbol</item>
                <item>Stick of Incense</item>
                <item>Vestments</item>
                <item>Belt Pouch</item>
                <item>Shortsword</item>
                <item>Shortbow</item>
                <item>Quiver</item>
                <item>Arrows</item>
                <item>Dungeoneer's Pack</item>
                <item>Leather Armor</item>
                <item>Dagger</item>
                <item>Thieves' Tools</item>
                <item>Common clothes</item>
                <item>Backpack</item>
                <item>Crowbar</item>
                <item>Hammer</item>
                <item>Piton</item>
                <item>Torch</item>
                <item>Tinderbox</item>
                <item>Rations</item>
                <item>Waterskin</item>
                <item>Hempen rope</item>
            </inventory>
            <!-- imagen -->
            <img>rogue</img>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://https://www.dndbeyond.com/classes/rogue</link>
        </character>
        <!-- nivel -->
        <character level="1" id="b6">
            <!-- clases -->
            <class>
                <name>Wizard</name>
                <levels>1</levels>
            </class>
            <!-- datos basicos -->
            <race> High Elf</race>
            <ac>13</ac>
            <hitpoints>7</hitpoints>
            <!-- competencias -->
            <proficiencies>
                <armor>no</armor>
                <weapon>dagger, dart, ligth crossbow, longbow, longsword, quarterstaff, shortbow,
                    shortsword, sling</weapon>
                <tool>no</tool>
                <saving_throw>int, wis</saving_throw>
                <skill>arcana, history, investigation, medicine, perception</skill>
            </proficiencies>
            <!-- espacios de conjuro -->
            <spell_slot>
                <lv1>2</lv1>
                <lv2>0</lv2>
                <lv3>0</lv3>
                <lv4>0</lv4>
                <lv5>0</lv5>
                <lv6>0</lv6>
                <lv7>0</lv7>
                <lv8>0</lv8>
                <lv9>0</lv9>
            </spell_slot>
            <!-- puntuaciones de caracteristicas -->
            <stats>
                <str>10</str>
                <dex>16</dex>
                <con>13</con>
                <int>16</int>
                <wis>10</wis>
                <cha>10</cha>
            </stats>
            <!-- dotes -->
            <features>
                <feature>Ritual Casting: You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has
                    the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don’t need to have
                    the spell prepared.</feature>
                <feature>Arcane Recovery: You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by
                    studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can
                    choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined
                    level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and
                    none of the slots can be 6th level or higher. For example, if you’re a 4th-level
                    wizard, you can recover up to two levels worth of spell slots. You can recover
                    either a 2nd-level spell slot or two 1st-level spell slots.</feature>
                <feature>Fey Ancestry: You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed,
                    and magic can’t put you to sleep.</feature>
                <feature>Trance: Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining
                    semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is
                    “trance.”) While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are
                    actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice.
                    After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8
                    hours of sleep.</feature>
                <feature>Darkvision: Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have
                    superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60
                    feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light.
                    You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</feature>
            </features>
            <!-- objetos -->
            <inventory>
                <item>Arcane Focus</item>
                <item>Dagger</item>
                <item>Explorer's Pack</item>
                <item>Spellbook</item>
                <item>Backpack</item>
                <item>Bedroll</item>
                <item>Mess Kit</item>
                <item>Tinderbox</item>
                <item>Torch</item>
                <item>Ration</item>
                <item>Waterskin</item>
                <item>Hempen Rope</item>
            </inventory>
            <!-- imagen -->
            <img>wizard</img>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://https://www.dndbeyond.com/classes/wizard</link>
        </character>
    </characters>
    <!-- conjuros -->
    <spels>
        <spell school="Conjuration" id="a1">
            <name>Acid Splash</name>
            <class>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Acid</tag>
                <tag>Damage </tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You hurl a bubble of acid. Choose one or two creatures you can see within range.
                If you choose two, they must be within 5 feet of each other. A target must succeed
                on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 acid damage. This spell’s damage increases
                by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6). </desc>
            <price>47</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/acid-splash</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Necromancy" id="a2">
            <name>Chill Touch</name>
            <class>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Necrotic</tag>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Round</cast>
            <desc> You create a ghostly, skeletal hand in the space of a creature within range. Make
                a ranged spell attack against the creature to assail it with the chill of the grave.
                On a hit, the target takes 1d8 necrotic damage, and it can't regain hit points until
                the start of your next turn. Until then, the hand clings to the target. If you hit
                an undead target, it also has disadvantage on attack rolls against you until the end
                of your next turn. This spell's damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level
                (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8). </desc>
            <price>498</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/chill-touch</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a3">
            <name>Control Flames</name>
            <class>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
                <name>DRUID</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Control</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You choose nonmagical flame that you can see within range and that fits within a
                5-foot cube. You affect it in one of the following ways: You instantaneously expand
                the flame 5 feet in one direction, provided that wood or other fuel is present in
                the new location. You instantaneously extinguish the flames within the cube. You
                double or halve the area of bright light and dim light cast by the flame, change its
                color, or both. The change lasts for 1 hour. You cause simple shapes—such as the
                vague form of a creature, an inanimate object, or a location—to appear within the
                flames and animate as you like. The shapes last for 1 hour. If you cast this spell
                multiple times, you can have up to three of its non-instantaneous effects active at
                a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action. </desc>
            <price>13</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/control-flames</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Conjuration" id="a4">
            <name>Create Bonfire</name>
            <class>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>DRUID</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Fire</tag>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
                <tag>Control</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You create a bonfire on ground that you can see within range. Until the spell
                ends, the magic bonfire fills a 5-foot cube. Any creature in the bonfire’s space
                when you cast the spell must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d8 fire
                damage. A creature must also make the saving throw when it moves into the bonfire’s
                space for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there. The bonfire ignites
                flammable objects in its area that aren’t being worn or carried. The spell’s damage
                increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level
                (4d8). </desc>
            <price>53</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/create-bonfire</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Evocation" id="a5">
            <name>Dancing Lights</name>
            <class>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>BARD</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Utility</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You create up to four torch-sized lights within range, making them appear as
                torches, lanterns, or glowing orbs that hover in the air for the duration. You can
                also combine the four lights into one glowing vaguely humanoid form of Medium size.
                Whichever form you choose, each light sheds dim light in a 10-foot radius. As a
                bonus action on your turn, you can move the lights up to 60 feet to a new spot
                within range. A light must be within 20 feet of another light created by this spell,
                and a light winks out if it exceeds the spell's range. </desc>
            <price>32</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/dancing-lights</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a6">
            <name>Druidcraft</name>
            <class>
                <name>DRUID</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Control</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> Whispering to the spirits of nature, you create one of the following effects
                within range: You create a tiny, harmless sensory effect that predicts what the
                weather will be at your location for the next 24 hours. The effect might manifest as
                a golden orb for clear skies, a cloud for rain, falling snowflakes for snow, and so
                on. This effect persists for 1 round. You instantly make a flower blossom, a seed
                pod open, or a leaf bud bloom. You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect,
                such as falling leaves, a puff of wind, the sound of a small animal, or the faint
                odor of skunk. The effect must fit in a 5-foot cube. You instantly light or snuff
                out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire. </desc>
            <price>12</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/druidcraft</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a7">
            <name>Eldritch Blast</name>
            <class>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> A beam of crackling energy streaks toward a creature within range. Make a ranged
                spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 force damage. The
                spell creates more than one beam when you reach higher levels: two beams at 5th
                level, three beams at 11th level, and four beams at 17th level. You can direct the
                beams at the same target or at different ones. Make a separate attack roll for each
                beam. </desc>
            <price>123</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/eldritch-blast</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Evocation" id="a8">
            <name>Fire Bolt</name>
            <class>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You hurl a mote of fire at a creature or object within range. Make a ranged spell
                attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 fire damage. A flammable
                object hit by this spell ignites if it isn't being worn or carried. This spell's
                damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and
                17th level (4d10). </desc>
            <price>5</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/fire-bolt</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Evocation" id="a9">
            <name>Frostbite</name>
            <class>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
                <name>DRUID</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
                <tag>Debuff</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You cause numbing frost to form on one creature that you can see within range.
                The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes
                1d6 cold damage, and it has disadvantage on the next weapon attack roll it makes
                before the end of its next turn. The spell’s damage increases by 1d6 when you reach
                5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6). </desc>
            <price>76</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/frostbite</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Divination" id="a10">
            <name>Guidance</name>
            <class>
                <name>CLERIC</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>DRUID</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Buff</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You touch one willing creature. Once before the spell ends, the target can roll a
                d4 and add the number rolled to one ability check of its choice. It can roll the die
                before or after making the ability check. The spell then ends. </desc>
            <price>32</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/guidance</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a11">
            <name>Gust</name>
            <class>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>DRUID</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Control</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You seize the air and compel it to create one of the following effects at a point
                you can see within range: One Medium or smaller creature that you choose must
                succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed up to 5 feet away from you. You
                create a small blast of air capable of moving one object that is neither held nor
                carried and that weighs no more than 5 pounds. The object is pushed up to 10 feet
                away from you. It isn’t pushed with enough force to cause damage. You create a
                harmless sensory effect using air, such as causing leaves to rustle, wind to slam
                shutters shut, or your clothing to ripple in a breeze. </desc>
            <price>37</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/gust</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Evocation" id="a12">
            <name>Light</name>
            <class>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>BARD</name>
                <name>CLERIC</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Creation</tag>
                <tag>Utility</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You touch one object that is no larger than 10 feet in any dimension. Until the
                spell ends, the object sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an
                additional 20 feet. The light can be colored as you like. Completely covering the
                object with something opaque blocks the light. The spell ends if you cast it again
                or dismiss it as an action. If you target an object held or worn by a hostile
                creature, that creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw to avoid the spell. </desc>
            <price>39</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/light</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Conjuration" id="a13">
            <name>Mage Hand</name>
            <class>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>BARD</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Utility</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> A spectral, floating hand appears at a point you choose within range. The hand
                lasts for the duration or until you dismiss it as an action. The hand vanishes if it
                is ever more than 30 feet away from you or if you cast this spell again. You can use
                your action to control the hand. You can use the hand to manipulate an object, open
                an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or
                pour the contents out of a vial. You can move the hand up to 30 feet each time you
                use it. The hand can't attack, activate magic items, or carry more than 10 pounds. </desc>
            <price>98</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/mage-hand</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a14">
            <name>Magic Stone</name>
            <class>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>DRUID</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You touch one to three pebbles and imbue them with magic. You or someone else can
                make a ranged spell attack with one of the pebbles by throwing it or hurling it with
                a sling. If thrown, it has a range of 60 feet. If someone else attacks with the
                pebble, that attacker adds your spellcasting ability modifier, not the attacker’s,
                to the attack roll. On a hit, the target takes bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 +
                your spellcasting ability modifier. Hit or miss, the spell then ends on the stone.
                If you cast this spell again, the spell ends early on any pebbles still affected by
                it. </desc>
            <price>97</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/magic-stone</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a15">
            <name>Mending</name>
            <class>
                <name>BARD</name>
                <name>CLERIC</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>DRUID</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
            </class>
            <tags>
                <tag>Utility</tag>
            </tags>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <cast>1 Minute</cast>
            <desc> This spell repairs a single break or tear in an object you touch, such as a
                broken chain link, two halves of a broken key, a torn cloak, or a leaking wineskin.
                As long as the break or tear is no larger than 1 foot in any dimension, you mend it,
                leaving no trace of the former damage. This spell can physically repair a magic item
                or construct, but the spell can't restore magic to such an object.</desc>
            <price>94</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/mending</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a16">
            <name>Message</name>
            <class>
                <name>BARD</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Social</tag>
                <tag>Comunication</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You point your finger toward a creature within range and whisper a message. The
                target (and only the target) hears the message and can reply in a whisper that only
                you can hear. You can cast this spell through solid objects if you are familiar with
                the target and know it is beyond the barrier. Magical silence, 1 foot of stone, 1
                inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood blocks the spell. The
                spell doesn't have to follow a straight line and can travel freely around corners or
                through openings.</desc>
            <price>93</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/message</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Illusion" id="a17">
            <name>Minor Illusion</name>
            <class>
                <name>BARD</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Control</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You create a sound or an image of an object within range that lasts for the
                duration. The illusion also ends if you dismiss it as an action or cast this spell
                again. If you create a sound, its volume can range from a whisper to a scream. It
                can be your voice, someone else's voice, a lion's roar, a beating of drums, or any
                other sound you choose. The sound continues unabated throughout the duration, or you
                can make discrete sounds at different times before the spell ends. If you create an
                image of an object--such as a chair, muddy footprints, or a small chest--it must be
                no larger than a 5-foot cube. The image can't create sound, light, smell, or any
                other sensory effect. Physical interaction with the image reveals it to be an
                illusion, because things can pass through it. If a creature uses its action to
                examine the sound or image, the creature can determine that it is an illusion with a
                successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a
                creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the illusion becomes faint to the
                creature.</desc>
            <price>96</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/minor-illusion</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a18">
            <name>Mold Earth</name>
            <class>
                <name>DRUID</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Control</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You choose a portion of dirt or stone that you can see within range and that fits
                within a 5-foot cube. You manipulate it in one of the following ways: If you target
                an area of loose earth, you can instantaneously excavate it, move it along the
                ground, and deposit it up to 5 feet away. This movement doesn’t have enough force to
                cause damage. You cause shapes, colors, or both to appear on the dirt or stone,
                spelling out words, creating images, or shaping patterns. The changes last for 1
                hour. If the dirt or stone you target is on the ground, you cause it to become
                difficult terrain. Alternatively, you can cause the ground to become normal terrain
                if it is already difficult terrain. This change lasts for 1 hour. If you cast this
                spell multiple times, you can have no more than two of its non-instantaneous effects
                active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an actio</desc>
            <price>74</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/mold-earth</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Conjuration" id="a19">
            <name>Poison Spray</name>
            <class>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>DRUID</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
                <tag>Poison</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You extend your hand toward a creature you can see within range and project a
                puff of noxious gas from your palm. The creature must succeed on a Constitution
                saving throw or take 1d12 poison damage. This spell's damage increases by 1d12 when
                you reach 5th level (2d12), 11th level (3d12), and 17th level (4d12).</desc>
            <price>76</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/poison-spray</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a20">
            <name>Prestidigitation</name>
            <class>
                <name>BARD</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Utility</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> This spell is a minor magical trick that novice spellcasters use for practice.
                You create one of the following magical effects within range: You create an
                instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind,
                faint musical notes, or an odd odor. You instantaneously light or snuff out a
                candle, a torch, or a small campfire. You instantaneously clean or soil an object no
                larger than 1 cubic foot. You chill, warm, or flavor up to 1 cubic foot of nonliving
                material for 1 hour. You make a color, a small mark, or a symbol appear on an object
                or a surface for 1 hour. You create a nonmagical trinket or an illusory image that
                can fit in your hand and that lasts until the end of your next turn. If you cast
                this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its non-instantaneous effects
                active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.</desc>
            <price>15</price>
            <!-- link -->
            <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/prestidigitation</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Conjuration" id="a21">
            <name>Produce Flame</name>
            <class>
                <name>DRUID</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Creation</tag>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
                <tag>Fire</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> A flickering flame appears in your hand. The flame remains there for the duration
                and harms neither you nor your equipment. The flame sheds bright light in a 10-foot
                radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. The spell ends if you dismiss it as
                an action or if you cast it again. You can also attack with the flame, although
                doing so ends the spell. When you cast this spell, or as an action on a later turn,
                you can hurl the flame at a creature within 30 feet of you. Make a ranged spell
                attack. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 fire damage. This spell's damage increases by
                1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</desc>
            <price>17</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/produce-flame</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Abjuration" id="a22">
            <name>Resistance</name>
            <class>
                <name>CLERIC</name>
                <name>DRUID</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Buff</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You touch one willing creature. Once before the spell ends, the target can roll a
                d4 and add the number rolled to one saving throw of its choice. It can roll the die
                before or after making the saving throw. The spell then ends.</desc>
            <price>19</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/resistance</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Evocation" id="a23">
            <name>Sacred Flame</name>
            <class>
                <name>CLERIC</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
                <tag>Radiant</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> Flame-like radiance descends on a creature that you can see within range. The
                target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d8 radiant damage. The
                target gains no benefit from cover for this saving throw. The spell's damage
                increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level
                (4d8).</desc>
            <price>27</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/sacred-flame</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Evocation" id="a24">
            <name>Shape Water</name>
            <class>
                <name>DRUID</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Control</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc> You choose an area of water that you can see within range and that fits within a
                5-foot cube. You manipulate it in one of the following ways: You instantaneously
                move or otherwise change the flow of the water as you direct, up to 5 feet in any
                direction. This movement doesn’t have enough force to cause damage. You cause the
                water to form into simple shapes and animate at your direction. This change lasts
                for 1 hour. You change the water’s color or opacity. The water must be changed in
                the same way throughout. This change lasts for 1 hour. You freeze the water,
                provided that there are no creatures in it. The water unfreezes in 1 hour. If you
                cast this spell multiple times, you can have no more than two of its
                non-instantaneous effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an
                action.</desc>
            <price>21</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/shape-water</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a25">
            <name>Shillelagh</name>
            <class>
                <name>DRUID</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
                <tag>Buff</tag>
                <tag>Bludgeoning</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc>The wood of a club or quarterstaff you are holding is imbued with nature's power.
                For the duration, you can use your spellcasting ability instead of Strength for the
                attack and damage rolls of melee attacks using that weapon, and the weapon's damage
                die becomes a d8. The weapon also becomes magical, if it isn't already. The spell
                ends if you cast it again or if you let go of the weapon.</desc>
            <price>28</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/shillelagh</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Necromancy" id="a26">
            <name>Spare the Dying</name>
            <class>
                <name>CLERIC</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Healing</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc>You touch a living creature that has 0 hit points. The creature becomes stable.
                This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.</desc>
            <price>29</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/spare-the-dying</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Transmutation" id="a27">
            <name>Thaumaturgy</name>
            <class>
                <name>CLERIC</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Control</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc>You manifest a minor wonder, a sign of supernatural power, within range. You
                create one of the following magical effects within range: Your voice booms up to
                three times as loud as normal for 1 minute. You cause flames to flicker, brighten,
                dim, or change color for 1 minute. You cause harmless tremors in the ground for 1
                minute. You create an instantaneous sound that originates from a point of your
                choice within range, such as a rumble of thunder, the cry of a raven, or ominous
                whispers. You instantaneously cause an unlocked door or window to fly open or slam
                shut. You alter the appearance of your eyes for 1 minute. If you cast this spell
                multiple times, you can have up to three of its 1-minute effects active at a time,
                and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.
            </desc>
            <price>27</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/thaumaturgy</link>
        </spell>
        

        <spell school="Evocation" id="a28">
            <name>Thunderwave</name>
            <class>
                <name>BARD</name>
                <name>DRUID</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
                <name>ARTIFICER</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
                <tag>Thunder</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc>You create a burst of thunderous sound that can be heard up to 100 feet away. Each
                creature within range, other than you, must succeed on a Constitution saving throw
                or take 1d6 thunder damage. The spell’s damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th
                level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6)</desc>
            <price>35</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/thunderwave</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Divination" id="a29">
            <name>True Strike</name>
            <class>
                <name>BARD</name>
                <name>SORCERER</name>
                <name>WARLOCK</name>
                <name>WIZARD</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Foreknowledge</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc>You point a finger at a target in range. Your magic grants you a brief insight
                into the target's defenses. On your next turn, you gain advantage on your first
                attack roll against the target, provided that this spell hasn't ended.</desc>
            <price>45</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/true-strike</link>
        </spell>

        <spell school="Enchantment" id="a30">
            <name>Vicious Mockery</name>
            <class>
                <name>BARD</name>
            </class>
            <!-- utilidad -->
            <tags>
                <tag>Damage</tag>
                <tag>Debuff</tag>
                <tag>Psychic</tag>
            </tags>
            <cast>1 Action</cast>
            <desc>You unleash a string of insults laced with subtle enchantments at a creature you
                can see within range. If the target can hear you (though it need not understand
                you), it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or take 1d4 psychic damage and have
                disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes before the end of its next turn. This
                spell's damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4),
                and 17th level (4d4).</desc>
            <price>48</price>
             <!-- link -->
             <link>https://www.dndbeyond.com/spells/vicious-mockery</link>
        </spell>
    </spels>
</dnd>